GLORY
DAYS!
The king that walks the path of
uniting all of China, Ying Zheng,
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
天下統一の道を行く王 嬴政(えいせい)のもと
has started an invasion of Qin's neighboring state, Wei.
秦国(しんこく)は 隣国 魏(ぎ)への侵攻を開始した
Wang Ben, Meng Tian, and Xin.
王賁(おうほん) 蒙恬(もうてん) そして信(しん)
未来の大将軍たらんとする兵(つわもの)が
今ここに集い―
Three soldiers who wish to someday become generals are gathered here trying to usher in a new era.
新しき時代を迎えようとしていた
（渕(えん)）あっ…
Lord Xin, look!
信どの あれを！
（信）ハッ…
What is it?!
どうした？
（渕）せっかく
玉鳳(ぎょくほう)隊が拠点を作ったのに―
Even though the Yufeng Unit finally
managed to form a base,
the ladder units aren't following after them.
ハシゴ部隊が
それに続いていません
ハッ…
（羌瘣(きょうかい)）恐らく―
Most likely this is the Yufeng Unit's solo surprise attack that the other units know nothing about.
これは ほかの部隊が
知らない 玉鳳隊の単独奇襲だ
But then...
しかし それでは…
（信）ああ
Yeah...
The Yufeng Unit is fighting alone and unassisted inside a huge enemy army!
（信）
玉鳳隊は 大軍の中に孤立無援だ
But...
（蒙恬）でも ここまでは 初めから
予定どおりだったんだろう？
this is what you planned from the beginning, right?
So why don't you show us
そこから何ができるのか…
what you can do from there, Wang Ben?
見せてもらおうか 王賁
（王賁）フン…
My Way of Fighting
（魏兵）殺せー！
Kill them!
（魏兵）そのまま すりつぶせ！
Crush them to a pulp!
Kill them!
殺せー！
（魏兵）押し込めー！
Corner them!
It's flowed considerably over to the left.
（じい）
だいぶ左に押し流されましたな
あれでは
もう 守備の要の壁長は討てない
Over there, they won't be able to attack the cornerstone of their defense, the wall chief.
Ah, I see.
ああ なるほどね
The guys who set up that smokescreen are waiting there on their horses.
下で煙幕張った連中が―
馬に乗ったまま待機してる
（副官）ハハッ！
ヤツら 虫の息ですぞ 将軍
They're at death's door, General!
（風伯(ふうはく)）う～む…
（番陽(ばんよう)）フハハハッ！ 賁さま！
Lord Ben!
You truly are a terrifying person...
あなたは本当に―
恐ろしいお方だ
Defensive circle formation!
防陣“円”！
What?
（兵士）何だ？
（兵士）どうした？
What just happened?
（副官）
拠点を作った… あんな所に
They formed a base point... in a place like that?
う～む…
Rope?
縄？
Your head... was never my goal to begin with.
初めから―
お前の首など眼中にない
C-Coult they be...?! That is...
ま… まさか あの場所は…
directly above the castle gate!
城門の真上だ！
Be careful, gate soldiers!
（風伯）気をつけろ 門兵！
敵が来るぞ！
Enemy incoming!
（どよめき）
（守備兵）敵だ！
Enemies!
They're trying to open the gate!
ヤツら 門を開ける気だ！
Kill them!
（守備兵）殺せ！
（守備兵）開けさせるな！
Don't let them open it!
You're too late.
もう遅い
The reason that unit was holding under the smokescreen
煙幕部隊を
そのまま下に とどめたのは―
was to invade the castle as soon as the gate was opened from the inside.
内から門を開けると同時に
城内へ侵入させるため
この作戦には 一切のムダがない
Nothing in this plan was a waste whatsoever.
Who would ever believe that this plan came from such a young general?
これが 年若き将から
編み出されたと 誰が信じる？
皆の者 今より刮目(かつもく)しておくがよい
Everyone, you had best have your eyes on this one from now on.
This is the capability of a man whose name will someday soon echo across the world, Wang Ben!
これが 近いうちに―
天下に名をとどろかすであろう
王賁さまの実力だ！
開門！
Open the gate!
（蒙恬）ヒャッホ～！
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
ンンッ！
ンンッ…
一体 何が起きてやがるんだ？
What the hell is going on?!
What?!
なんだと！
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
城壁を守る壁長たちは言葉を失った
The wall chiefs guarding the other castle walls were flabbergasted.
When they realized what had happened, they saw the State of Qin flag flying on the main castle.
気づけば 城主のいる本城に
秦国の旗が立っていたのである
In other words... Gaolang Castle had fallen.
つまり―
高狼(こうろう)城 陥落である
The invasion of the Yuehua Unit, led by Meng Tian, through the castle gate to the capturing of the castle
蒙恬率いる楽華(がくか)隊の城門突入から
本城 陥落まで 正に―
was truly done with lightning speed.
電光石火の早業であった
Yuehua Unit, what the hell do you think you're doing?!
（伍長(ごちょう)）楽華隊！
（伍長）
貴様ら 一体 何のつもりだ？
城門を破りしは 我ら玉鳳
それを横から手柄を奪うとは！
We, the Yufeng Unit are the ones that broke through the gate! How dare you step in and take our achievement!
（伍長）これを盗っ人(と)と呼ばずに
何と言う！ 恥を知れ！
You can't call this anything but thievery! Do you know no shame?!
Who are you calling thieves?!
（伍長）誰が盗っ人か！
（伍長）
貴様ら 蒙恬さまを侮辱するか！
Are you insulting Lord Meng Tian?!
Of course we're insulting him!
侮辱されて当然だ！
大体 お前ら楽華隊は いつもいつも
Geez, you Yuehua Unit bastards are always...
おう 何だ？ 言ってみろ
What? Spit it out!
おう 今日こそ言わせてもらうぞ
Okay! Today we're gonna speak our minds!
Let's go, Xin.
（尾平(びへい)）
行こうぜ 信　俺らには関係ねえ
This is none of our business.
You're the ones that did that!
それは お前らのほうだろう！
（王賁）もういい　やめろ
That's enough.
They were free to go through the opened gate.
開いた門を通るのはヤツらの自由だ
The problem lies rather with us, as the ones that crossed over first.
問題は むしろ ヤツらに
先を越された我らのほうにある
Lord Wang Ben...
王賁さま…
（伍長）王賁さま…
Lord Wang Ben.
そうそう そのとおり
（伍長）蒙恬 貴様！
Yes, yes, exactly.
Meng Tian, you bastard!
ハハハッ… 冗談
ひとつ借りができたとは思ってるよ
Just kidding.
I think I owe you one for that.
ちゃんと いつか返すから
I'll make sure to pay you back someday.
No need.
要らん　その代わり 次から―
I'll just remember to dig a pitfall in front of you as part of my next strategy.
お前らの前に 落とし穴を
作るところまで作戦に入れておく
Oh, sounds scary!
ハハッ… それ怖いなぁ　うん？
Hey! Xin from the Feixin Unit!
お～い 飛信(ひしん)隊の信君！
そんなとこで見てないで
こっち上がってきなよ
Don't watch from all the way over there! Come up here!
Let's go.
行くぞ
（伍長）ははっ！
Yes, sir!
あら？
Oh? Not even gonna say "good job" to those guys?
彼らにも“お疲れさん”くらい
ないのかい？
I don't talk with losers.
敗者と話すことなどない
ンッ… 誰が敗者だ！ てめえ 王賁
大体 てめえら 卑怯(ひきょう)なんだよ！
Who're you calling a loser?!
Wang Ben, you bastard!
You don't play fair, you know!
Dragging out that huge thing!
あんな でけえ物(もん) 持ち出しやがって
If we had that thing, we could've taken down a damn castle wall!
あんな物がありゃ 俺らだって
城壁 破るくらいできるっつうんだ
（王賁）剣の才を持つ者が
剣を振るうのは卑怯じゃないように
Just as it is not unfair for one who is talented with a sword to swing a sword,
I only used the siege tower because I had it with me.
俺は 井蘭車(せいらんしゃ)を持っていたから
使っただけだ　妙な難癖をつけるな
Don't try to place meaningless blame on me.
It's one of the talents of those of high birth.
名門の出も才能のひとつだ
Bastard!
てめえ！
（蒙恬）ハハッ… ドウドウ
Now, now.
そう熱くなるなよ
まだ１コ目の城だ
Don't get so uptight. This is just the first castle.
The campaign is only just...
遠征は これから… うん？
Huh? Some sorta smoke!
うん？ 何だ？ なんか煙いぞ
Fire!
（兵士）火だ！
（兵士）町から火が上がってるぞ！
There's fire rising from the city!
No way...
まさか…
Wait.
（蒙恬）待て
（信）ンッ…
俺たちが関わることじゃない
This isn't something for us to get involved in.
何言ってんだ！ 離せ バカ野郎！
What're you talking about?! Let me go, you idiot!
Hey, Xin!
（尾平）おい 信！
Xin!
信！
（渕）信どの！
Lord Qiang Lei, please look after things here!
羌瘣どの ここは お願いします
Wh... What the fuck are you bastards doing?!
何やってんだ てめえら！
Don't, Lord Xin!
ダメです 信どの！ 抑えるんだ
Control yourself!
離せ 渕さん！ なんで止めるんだ！
（渕）彼らは味方です！
Let me go Mr. Yuan! Why're you stopping?!
They're our allies!
Attacking comrades is a major crime!
同士討ちは重罪
下手すれば斬首になります
If you mess up badly, it could be your head!
What's with those guys...?
（乱銅(らんどう)）何だ？ あいつら
Hey, bastards!
（乱銅）おい てめえら！
ここは 俺の千人隊の持ち場だ
This is the post of our Thousand Man Unit!
獲物が欲しけりゃ ほかへ行け
If you want prey, then try someplace else!
野郎！
（渕）し… 信どの！
Bastard!
L-Lord Xin!
離せ！
（渕）みんな 信どのを！
Let me go!
Everyone, grab Lord Xin!
離してくれ 渕さん！
（渕）信どの！
You've gotta let me go Mr. Yuan!
Lord Xin!
This is the real world!
これが現実なんです！
We've been thinking about nothing
but rendering achievements,
（渕）我々は
武功のことばかり考えてきましたが
but this is an invasion after all.
この戦いは 結局は侵略
It's unfortunate, but scenes like this are sure to occur.
残念ですが こういう場面は
必ず付いて回ります　必ず…
I know.
（信）
分かってる… 俺だって分かってる
I'm at least smart enough to know...
戦が きれい事じゃねえことくらい
that war isn't pretty.
But still...
だけど だからって…
（握り締める音）
do you think I could just sit by and watch this happen?!
こんなの 黙って見過ごせるかよ…
We don't have to just sit by.
見過ごしは しませんよ
軍には軍律があるんです
Armies have military law.
We'll stop that unit's captain from committing these violations immediately!
そこの隊の隊長は 今すぐ
この蹂躙(じゅうりん)行為をやめさせられよ！
The enemy has already surrendered!
敵は 既に降伏した！
これは 明らかに軍律違反だ
This is a clear violation of military law!
We'll be reporting these acts to our superiors!
このことは あとで上に報告する
これ以上
罪を重ねぬほうが身のためだ！
It would be in your best interest to not commit anymore crimes!
ああ あいつら そういうことか
（部下）チッ… ウザイっすね
Oh, so that's what these guys are on about.
Noisy, ain't they?
I'm Thousand Man General Luan Tong!
千人将の乱銅だ
すっ込んでろ！
戦のことも知らねえ青くせえ連中が
Get out of here,
you greenhorns that don't know a thing about war!
降伏した相手をやらねえ軍律など
I'd like you to show me one army
where a law saying you can't kill an enemy that's surrendered is actually enforced!
実際 どこの軍隊でも
あって ないようなもんなんだよ
This is a privilege given to the victors.
これが
勝者に与えられる特権ってもんだ
Pound this into your skull!
（乱銅）
よ～く頭に たたき込んどけ
Nearly one hundred of my men died in this war.
この戦で 部下が100人近く死んだ
Stop!
やめろ！
But it doesn't matter how many Wei bastards die!
魏国のヤツらが何人死のうが
関係ねえだろうが！
この野郎ーっ！
You bastard!
ハハッ… バカが　先に抜いたぞ
That moron. He jumped out on his own.
殺して かまわん
（部下）へい
I don't care if you kill him!
Lord Xin! You must not kill them!
信どの！ 殺しては いかん！
（蹴る音）
（部下たち）ウワッ！
こいつだけは！
This guy, I can't forgive!
（蒙恬）やめろ 信！
Stop, Xin!
Meng Tian!
（渕）蒙恬…
（蒙恬）分かってるだろうが
I think you know this, but if you kill a Thousand Man General, you'll lose everything!
千人将なんか斬れば
お前は全てを失うぞ
Everything!
全てをだ！
Shut up!
（信）うるせえ！
Xin. Is that all the conviction you had...
（蒙恬）信…
お前の 大将軍への思いは―
for becoming a Great General?
Meng Tian
そんなものか
（信）ンンッ…
（乱銅）こいつ…
This brat...
てめえ 今 何をしようとしてんのか
分かってんだろうな？
You know what you're trying to do, right?
てめえみてえな下っ端が
千人将の この俺をやれば―
If a low-ranker like you kills me, a Thousand Man General,
確実に てめえは斬首
they'll behead you for sure.
And on top of that, your comrades will get dragged into it, too.
おまけに 仲間も全員 とばっちりを
受けることになるからな
What that man is saying is true.
その男の言っていることは本当だ
Sheathe your sword, Xin.
剣を納めろ 信
ンンッ！
（乱銅）ウッ！ てめえ…
Bastard...
Stop those abominable acts your underlings are committing right now.
今すぐ
手下どもの外道な行いをやめさせろ
そして この先
And swear you'll never lay a hand on people who've surrendered ever again!
二度と 降伏した住人に
手を出さねえと誓いやがれ！
ハハハッ… バ～カ
You idiot.
やめさせねえし この先も
ずっと敗者をいたぶりまくってやる
You can't stop me.
I'm gonna keep tormenting losers all I want.
I told you, I'm fightin' these wars because I have so much fun doin' that!
それが楽しいから戦争やってる…
…つってんだろうが！
（蹴る音）
Guys like you that know nothing about the real world and try to act the hero
てめえみてえに
現実知らねえ正義漢気取りが―
piss me off more than anyone else!
いっちばんムカつくんだよ！
てめえ… やりやが…
You bastard... you really did...
Guys like you that spout stuff about how "this is reality"
俺は てめえみてえな
“現実 現実”っつって―
くだらねえこと正当化するヤツが
いちばんムカつくんだよ！
and to try to justify your bullshit, piss me off more than anyone else!
Because everyone else does it ain't any sort of excuse!
“みんな やってるから”なんて
何の言い訳にもなってねえ
外道は外道だ！
An abomination's an abomination!
I, Xin of the Feixin Unit,
飛信隊の信は―
どんな理由であろうと
そんなヤツは絶対に許さねえ！
will never forgive such a person no matter what reason they give!
Whether my opponent's a Thousand Man General, a Full General,
相手が千人将だろうが将軍だろうが
王さまだろうが関係ねえ！
or a king, I don't care!
それが これまでも これからも―
That's the way of fighting I've always had and always will!
ずっと
変わることのねえ俺のやり方だ！
So to just pretend I didn't see this sorta thing because I'm afraid of punishment...
処罰が怖(こえ)えからって
こんなのを見て見ぬフリなんざして
how the hell could I be the greatest general under the heavens?!
なにが天下の大将軍だ！
Xin!
（尾平）信！
（部下）な… 何だ？ あいつら
What's with that guy?!
それより あいつを殺せ！
（部下）千人将の敵(かたき)だ！
Nevermind, kill him!
Avenge the Thousand Man General!
Wait! That's the Feixin Unit, famous on the East lines.
（副長）待て！ あれは
東の前線で有名だった飛信隊だ
あれが？
They are?!
But he killed our Thousand Man General, we can't just...
だけど
千人将がやられて このまま…
What? Don't worry about it.
なぁに 心配すんな
He cut down a Thousand Man General.
千人将を斬ったんだ
He'll be court-martialed and beheaded.
どうせ あいつは
軍法会議にかけられて 斬首になる
What?! You've gotta be kidding me!
（副長）
ああ？ ふざけんじゃねえ！
Why is he getting off scot-free and we have to go through an interrogation?!
なんで あいつが無罪放免で―
俺たちが
尋問を受けなきゃならねえんだ！
He didn't get off scot-free.
He's being imprisoned for one night.
（取調官）無罪放免ではない
一夜 投獄される
The Thousand Man General Luan Tong attacked him first.
先に 千人将 乱銅が斬りかかり―
So as Xin of the Feixin Unit cut him down unwillingly, his punishment is light.
やむなく
斬り伏せた飛信隊 信の罪は軽い
乱銅の傷も
そこまで深くなかったと聞く
I've also heard that Luan Tong's wound was not particularly deep.
On the other hand, your exceptional acts of barbarity on people that had already surrendered
一方 降伏した者たちに加えた
そなたたちの度を超えた蛮行は―
軍法会議にかけるとのことだ
is a matter worthy of court-martial.
The approval has been given, now come with me.
裁可は下ったのだ　さっさと来い！
まずは副長のお前からだ
We'll start with you, the vice captain.
お… おい 離せ バカ野郎！
いいか？ よく聞けよ
Hey, let me go, you jackasses!
Wait, listen! It wasn't just us!
俺たちだけじゃねえぞ
みんな やってんだ！ 今だってよ…
Everyone was doing it!
Even now, they're...
Thank goodness.
良かった… いくら
千人将の命が無事だったとはいえ
Even though we'd heard that the Thousand Man General is still alive,
信どのの首が落とされるかと
ヒヤヒヤしていましたよ 私
I was still fearful Lord Xin might lose his head.
Does this happen often?
よくあることなのか？
（渕）はい？
Hm?
Nothing. It's just that this ended in a surprisingly good result for us.
いや こちらにとって 随分
都合のいい結果に終わったからな
Ah, you have a point...
ああ 確かに
Lord Qiang Lei?
羌瘣どの？
Okay, you guys get over here, too!
（取調官）
ほら！ お前らも さっさと来い！
（部下）いてっ！ 離せよ！
Ow! Let me go!
Are you pleased, Young Master?
（羅元(らげん)）
あれで良かったのかな？ 若
You were a great help, General Luo Yuan.
助かりました 羅元将軍
この借りは 近いうちに必ず
I'll be sure to repay this favor soon.
ほう…
立派なことを言われるようになった
Oh. Looks like I'll be getting something good out of all this.
I'll be waiting in rapt anticipation.
大いに期待して待っていよう
So this is your doing?
（王賁）お前の仕業か…
（蒙恬）うん？
Wang Ben.
王賁
Unlike you, I'm not opposed to using my father's or grandfather's authority whatsoever.
俺は お前と違って―
祖父や父の威光を利用することに
何ら抵抗ないからね
このくらい強引に
事を収めるのは 簡単 簡単
Forcibly quieting things was an easy task.
Why did you save that guy?
なぜ あんなヤツを助けた？
He's utterly childish.
子供もいいところだ
三百人将にもなって
感情の制御もできんとは
To become a 300 Man General without even being able to control his emotions is remarkable.
斬首になろうと自業自得だ
If he was beheaded, it would be his own fault.
Cutting down one or two out-of-control Thousand Man Generals won't change a thing.
１人２人 暴走する千人将を
斬ったところで 何も変わらぬ
If he really wants to change something, the only way is to stand at the pinnacle of the army yourself.
本気で変えたいなら
自分が 軍の頂上に立つしかない
Exactly.
そのとおり
それが分かっているから
今の俺たちは蛮行を黙って見過ごす
It's because we know that
that you and I stand by overlooking these atrocities.
But ya know... I'm sure Xin is well aware of that as well.
でもね
それは
きっと信も 十分 分かってるよ
分かったうえで
なお あの行動に出た
He did what he did even knowing that.
He's straightforward in his convictions.
あいつは
自分の信念に まっすぐだよ
Straightforward, like a flying arrow.
まるで
放たれた火矢のように まっすぐ
He's got his own personal path towards becoming a Great General.
あいつは あいつで 自分なりの
大将軍への道を持ってるんだ
I like that man they call Xin of the Feixin Unit.
俺は好きになったな
飛信隊の信という男が
（王賁）
信念があろうと バカはバカだ
Conviction or not, a fool's a fool.
What's more, his starting point was fatally low.
おまけに ヤツは
致命的なほどに出発点が低すぎる
フッ… と言いつつ
実は 少～し思ってたりして
You say that, but I'll bet you've
actually thought about it a bit.
"Aw man, that guy might eventually become a pretty formidable opponent."
（蒙恬）
“意外と さきざき 手ごわい敵に
なりそうだ　やっべえ”って
Ridiculous.
（王賁）ふざけるな
Geez, let go already.
（兵士）もう手をかけさせんな
What're kids gonna do with their parents gone?
親も いなくなって
この先 どうすんだ？
Just do what we tell you to.
おとなしくしてりゃいいんだ
We'll get money and you'll live an easier life.
俺たちにも金が入るし
お前らも楽に暮らせるんだぞ
But will somebody this shabby really sell?
しかしよ こんな貧乏くせえの
売り物になるのか？
そうだな… ほか当たるか
You've got a point.
Maybe we should try somewhere else.
（兵士）バ～カ
（姉）えっ…
You moron.
If you don't bring us in any money, then there's no point in letting you live.
金になんねえんなら
生かしとく意味ねえだろう
ンンッ…
（兵士）子供だろうが―
Even if you're kids,
anyone from the State of Wei is our enemy.
魏国の連中は 俺たちの敵だからな
Th-Thank you so much.
あ… ありがとうございます
Are you all right?
大丈夫か？
（姉）は… はい
Y-Yes.
偉いな　妹をかばったのか？
（姉）姉ですから…
That was quite something. You protected your little sister?
Well, I'm her big sister.
妹の名は？
（姉）春(しゅん)です
What's your little sister's name?
It's Chun.
Chun, you can't just always rely on being helped by your big sister.
春 いつまでも泣くな
これからは 姉ちゃんに
助けてもらってばかりじゃダメだ
You need to have courage and help her, too, for both of your sakes.
お前も しっかりして 姉ちゃんと
力を合わせて生きていくんだ
You two are sisters after all.
お前たち２人は 姉妹なんだから
（春）はい…
Okay...
Can you walk?
歩けるか？
町の連中が集まっている所まで
連れていってやる
I'll bring you to a place where a lot of townspeople are gathered.
You should be all right there.
そこにいれば もう大丈夫だ
春 泣かないよ！
I won't cry anymore!
Want me to get you out?
出すか？
（信）いや いい　反省中だ
No, that's cool. I'm reflecting on what I've done.
But I really could've caused a lot of trouble for you and the rest of the unit.
なんでか
奇跡的に 軽い罰で助かったが
本当は お前や隊の仲間たちに
迷惑をかけるところだった
That's why I decided I'm gonna stay up all night searching my conscience.
だから俺は 今晩は
寝ずに反省することに決めたんだ
あの野郎を斬ったことは
後悔してないけどな
Not that I regret cutting that guy.
I see.
（羌瘣）そうか
Bye.
Hey, wait!
アアッ… 待て待て！ 暇だから
ちょっと話し相手になれよ
I've got some free time, so I could use someone to talk to for a bit!
You said you were reflecting.
今“反省する”って…
（信）あと 何か
食い物持ってきてくれ　腹減った
And get me something to eat afterwards. I'm hungry.
You've got to be kidding.
（羌瘣）ふざけるな
Thanks to Meng Tian's maneuvering, the uproar over Xin's attacking of the Thousand Man General Luo Yuan
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
信が 千人将 乱銅を斬った騒ぎは
蒙恬の工作により
大事には至らなかったが
did not turn into anything major.
And the Feixin Unit's name spread amongst the State of Qin Army and the State of Wei in a new way, albeit subtly.
飛信隊は 今までと違う形で
ささやかながらも―
秦国軍と魏国の者たちの間に
名を広めた
Meanwhile, the ones who gained military notoriety from this first battle
一方 この初戦で武名を上げたのは
玉鳳隊 王賁　楽華隊 蒙恬である
were Wang Ben of the Yufeng Unit and Meng Tian of the Yuehua Unit.
Thanks to their actions, the first castle, Gaolang, was captured in a mere eleven days.
両隊の活躍により 第１の城 高狼は
僅か11日で陥落した
And the next day,
そして この翌日
別動隊となっていた
蒙驁将軍の２人の副将も―
they received word that the two separate units led by General Meng Ao's Vice Generals
それぞれ
魏国の城を落としたと連絡が入る
captured Wei Castles as well.
It was a favorable start for the State of Qin Army.
秦国軍としては
順調な滑り出しとなったのである
But at this point, no one had realized
しかし
このときは誰も気づいていなかった
that later on in this campaign they would confront an unimaginably grand figure.
この遠征の先で―
思いも寄らぬ大人物と
対決することを
State of Wei
Daliang
The people of Qin have invaded my kingdom
（景湣王(けいびんおう)）秦の者どもが
我が国に侵攻し
King Jing Min
虚中(きょちゅう) 虚西(きょさい)まで
あっさりと陥落した
and easily captured everything from central to West Xu.
But the reason I am not shaken
whatsoever is because you are here.
だが―
我が心胆が
一切 震えることがないのは―
そなたがいるからだ
Former member of the State of Zhao Three Great Devas,
元趙国三大天(ちょうこく さんだいてん)
Great General Lian Po!
廉頗(れんぱ)大将軍
そなたが我が国に亡命してより３年
It has been three years since you defected to my kingdom.
There is nothing I have ever been more thankful for.
今ほど
ありがたく思ったことはないぞ
The Man Lian Po
End